

# DONIBEN JIMENEZ JARAMILLO

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

# **PROFILE**

+4 years Software Developer with communication skills in Spanish, English and Esperanto. Background experience in education, social processes, film production, and programming. I seek innovative ways to apply interdisciplinary knowledge to agile **Back-end** and **Front-end** software development. **React** and **VueJs** is where my skills are strongest.

# **SKILLS**

## FRONTEND

- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Bulma
- Tailwind
- React & React Native
- Styled-components
- Material-UI
- VueJs + Vuex
- Redux (Redux toolkit)
- Typescript

#### **BACKEND**

- Javascript (NodeJS + Express)
- Python (Django and Flask)
- Ruby on Rails (Junior)
- Kotlin (Junior)
- Solana Smart contracts
- BashScripting
- Databases: SQL, PostgresQl, MongoDB
- Linux servers, macOs, AWS serverless(lambdas, dynamoDB, Apigateway, Amplify, cloud watch, EC2, S3,)

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# JUN 2023 - Present [Mexico] Altán Redes · Full-time RESPONSABILITIES

- Cloud & Infrastructure Developer at Altán Redes, specializing in AWS services.
- Design & deploy robust EC2 server environments for telecom & mobile internet services.
- Develop & integrate PHP, Laravel, Perl, JS, and CGI apps within server environments.
- Utilize AWS Lambda functions for enhanced functionality & optimized performance.
- Implement API Gateway & Apigee for efficient & secure communication between systems.
- Create & manage AWS infrastructures for seamless connectivity to Mexican users.
- Collaborate with clients, understand requirements & provide tailored solutions.
- Ensure reliability & scalability to meet Altán Redes' network demands.
- Contribute to Mexico's connectivity mission with cutting-edge tech.

## FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# SEP 2020 - MAY 2023 [Colombia] The Data Culture, tdc-lab.com RESPONSIBILITIES

- Mobile and web full stack software engineer who specializes in JS technologies.
- Working on solutions for the metaverse, film editing, odontology, NFTs, education, and health industries
- As a **VueJs** and **React** Tech Lead, I **oversaw three other developers** in the of different user's dashboards, which included graphics, PDF history reports, patient/client management tables, shopping carts, calendar appointments, 3D experiences, and more.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Created an Android **film editor from scratch using Kotlin**, which reduced the editing time for glambot videos **from 20 minutes to just 2 minutes**. I achieved this by using **FFmpeg** flags that allowed the application to build custom presets based on the desired video style.
- Optimized the development processes for projects created from scratch by implementing good practices, Redux, and custom hooks.

#### FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# MAR 2021 - MAY 2022 [USA] 321ignition.com

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Created and supported web applications for car dealerships in the United States using SASS, Vue, JS, and microservices.
- Tech lead in one of the onboarding teams. Core developer for new features.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Improved the client template by optimizing components that received data, resulting in increased productivity **from 3 to 7 web applications per month.**
- Improved the onboarding training methodology for new developers, which process were taking 3 months. After just 1.5 months of my training, they were able to contribute to over 85% of the workflow.

#### JUNIOR RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER

#### FEB 2021 - MAY 2022 [Colombia] symplifica.com

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

 Learned Ruby on Rails to better understand and implement new features for the main app, and developed new core functions to improve working conditions for domestic service employees.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

• Integrated third-party payment methods to offer more options for clients when paying their employees.

#### LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### JAN 2021 - JUL 2021 [Colombia] MUSEO.COALICO.CO

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Created a virtual museum for the NGO COALICO, integrating VR technology, React, and serverless services from AWS.
- Participated throughout the entire planning process, making proposals based on the multimedia selected for the museum and the available technology.

#### **KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- The platform reached over 40 schools, becoming a new **didactic tool for teaching** about the violent history of Colombia.
- This museum is now a reference for social organizations as a means to **expand their action fields** and communicate about the contributions made by organizations working for peace, democratization of education, environmental protection, food sovereignty, public policies, human rights, cultural defense, and more, using technology.
- Thanks to the serverless tools provided by AWS, **the costs are kept to a minimum**, allowing the museum to remain operational for more than 10 years.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### 2017 - CURRENTLY | Own projects in https://doniben.com

- **Cipheak** (Language creator, Javascript technologies, algorithm based on esperanto's grammar to create billions of new artifitial languages just with a click.)
- 8x.social (link shortener, django),
- **Miscua** (covid-19 maptracking app to identify places where people easily get infected, react-native),
- esperanto.co (language comunity site, created with wordpress since 2017).
- Fruitmark Mobile app (Fullstack app with react-native and nodeJs for fruits administration in France)
- **Wiif app** (Fullstack mobile app with serverless backend to take information from clients who wants to rebuild or improve their home spaces).
- Muscha Social network created with Vue.js to motivate daily music instrument learning challenges based on smart contracts and VueJs. Coming soon.
- More projects hosted in github.com/Doniben.

# **EDUCATION**

# MAR 2021 - DIC 2021 | MISIÓN TIC - National Ministry of Technology

• Training in web application development

#### JUN 2019 - MAR 2020 | HOLBERTON SCHOOL

• Full Stack Software Engineer (Bash scripting, C, Python, linux severs, JavaScript, web)

#### 2009 - 2020 | Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

• B.A Social Sciences Teacher

#### 2013 - 2016 | Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje SENA

Technological Training in film scriptwriting (Audio production, video editing, photograpy)

# LANGUAGES

• Spanish • English • Esperanto • Learning Chinese